我看起来怎么样
Well, how do I look?
非常重要的一天 我要去见艾丽克斯
Big day. I'm going to see Alex.
我 我有点紧张
I'm, uh -- I'm a little nervous
因为她最近有点疏远我们
because she's been pulling away lately.
打电话也不回
Calls don't get returned.
也不像以前那样经常要我去看她了
I don't get asked to visit as much.
我有点承受不来
Maybe it's hitting me hard
可能是因为我和我爸从没有过类似情况
'cause I never went through that with my dad.
我上完第一年
After my junior year,
我们一起骑双人自行车穿过米克诺斯岛
we -- we rode a tandem bike across Mykonos.
仔细想想
Come to think of it,
那里有好多父子
there were lots of fathers and sons there.
菲尔 坐下
Phil, sit.
我们得谈谈鸭子的事情
We need to talk about the ducks.
我们讨厌那些鸭子
We hate the ducks.
又来 你有麻烦了
Again? You have a problem.
我听到不少抱怨
I'm hearing a lot of negatives,
但我们都忽略了小羽会捡东西的事实
but we're overlooking the fact that Feathers can now fetch.
亲爱的 它从水槽拖出了个湿漉漉的热狗面包
Honey, she pulled a wet hot dog bun out of the sink,
然后你才说"去捡面包"
and you said, "get the bun."
那可不算是捡东西
That doesn't count as fetching.
拜托别告诉它们要一直待在这里
Please tell me they're not gonna live here forever.
你可不配说这个
You're really not the one to make that argument.
说得你好像不会
Oh, like you're not gonna
睡在楼上那张双层床直到老死一样
die of natural causes in that bunk bed upstairs.
听着 我们给了它们一个美好的家
Look, we have provided them with a good home.
等它们准备好了 自然就会走了
When they're ready, they'll leave.
随时有可能
Could be any day.
顺便替鸭子说句公道话 克莱尔
Oh, and in the duck's defense, Claire,
你不能在吃早饭时故意把腿露在外面
You can't stick your leg out of your robe at breakfast
然后还假装讨厌别人看你
and then pretend to hate the attention.
你怎么没有努力抗争一下
Why didn't you fight harder about the ducks?
你听到他说了的吧
You heard what he said.
鸭子现在随时都有可能离开
The ducks could leave any day now.
是啊 也可能要到两个月后
Yeah, or it could be two months from now.
或者现在随时
Or any day now.
或者一个多月...
Or a month and a half fr--
你怎么就不明白呢
How are you not getting this?
米奇打电话问你什么时候把充气床垫带过去
Mitch called. He wants to know when are you bringing
好让莉莉的朋友来家里过夜
the air mattress for Lily's sleepover.
对于一个不肯自己买充气床垫的人来说
You know, for a guy who refuses to buy his own air mattresses,
他倒是很挑剔气垫什么时候送到啊
he's pretty particular about when they arrive.
不不不 别吃我的酱
No, no! Don't eat my sauce.
吃了就不够我拿去农夫市场上卖了
Then I won't have enough to sell at the farmers' market.
别 天哪 别戳我的嘟嘟肉
No. Oh, geez. Not the fat finger.
你总爱在我长胖时这么戳戳戳
You always do this when I put on a few.
我可什么都没说
I didn't say anything.
你说没说什么不重要
It's not what you say.
是你这该死的量油尺般的手指
It's that damn lard dipstick finger of yours.
第二指关节都陷进去了
It disappeared up to the second knuckle.
既然你们说完了
Well, now that that's over with,
我可以跟你们聊聊跟橄榄球有关的问题了吧
I can finally share my latest football-related problem.
米奇尔说得对 也许我是该送过去了
Mitchell's right. I should probably get a move on.
球队没有带我一起搞季末恶作剧
The team left me out of the end-of-the-season prank.
这让我想起了以前
You know, that takes me back.
我们跟学校董事会告状说戴维斯教练是个共产党
We told the school board that coach Davis was a communist.
结果害那家伙吃了两天牢饭
The man spent a weekend in jail.
多么简单粗暴
Simpler times.
那也比这些个白痴干的好啊
Well, that's better than what these meatheads cooked up.
他们只不过把校长的车
They just parked the principal's car
停在了篮球场中央
in the middle of the basketball court.
不应该把车停那里啊
That's not where cars go.
这些混蛋为什么不带上你
Why didn't those meatballs include you?
他们嫌我自命清高
They think I'm a goody-two-shoes.
我没有啊
I'm not.
连我自己老妈都这么说吗
My own mother?
我只说你偶尔犯点法也不会怎么样
Ay, I'm just saying it wouldn't kill you to break some rules.
你是个未成年人 要好好利用这一点
You're a minor. Take advantage of it.
我也会犯法啊
I break the rules.
我只是喜欢考究点的 要有派头又有手段的
I just prefer to be suave, do it with panache and finesse.
那些是美国的洗发水 我知道
Ay, those are American shampoos. I know.
准备好听这个消息了吗
Y'all ready for this?
我把我们的酱
I got our sauce
推销给了老爷爷节日礼品篮[礼品篮业的老祖]
into The Granddaddy of All Holiday gift baskets.
哪一个
Which one?
就叫做老爷爷节日礼品篮
It's called Granddaddy's Holiday Gift Baskets.
非常高级
Very exclusive.
他们要150罐
They want 150 jars...
今晚六点就要
6 o'clock tonight.
不行 这么短时间内做不出那么多啊
No! It's too much sauce for too little time.
而且我也没有关键食材了
And anyways, I don't have the key ingredient --
大红椒
The blood peppers.
我的堂兄要到下礼拜
And my cousin can't send me more
才能从哥伦比亚给我寄过来
from Colombia until next week.
比你早想到一步啦
One spicy step ahead of you.
有请塞拉诺辣椒
Enter the Serrano pepper!
没人会知道区别的
No one will know the difference.
我能
I will.
这酱是我继承传统的一部分
This sauce is part of my heritage.
我不能背弃我的身份
I cannot turn my back on who I am.
你的头发以前不是更深色一点吗
Didn't your hair used to be darker?
我是说
I'm just saying
这是推销我们的酱的大好时期
this is a great opportunity for our sauce.
我们的酱
"Our sauce"?
突然间 小卡管它叫"我们的酱"了
All of a sudden, Cam is calling it "our sauce"?
这个配方是我伯祖母给我的
I got that recipe from my great aunt
那可是她母亲从一个瞎女仆那里偷来后给她的
who got it from her mother who stole it from a blind maid.
他怎么敢这么说
How dare he.
好吧 我们就去弄点大红椒
Fine. We'll just go get some blood peppers.
不可能买到的
They're impossible to get.
除非你愿意犯点法
Unless you're willing to break some rules.
我们为什么说回你的事情了
Why are we back on your thing again?
正好有人在植物园里
They just so happen to grow blood peppers
种了大红椒
at the botanical gardens.
太好了 我们走吧
Great. Let's go.
你太天真了
You're adorable.
我说的可是有被严密保护起来的珍稀植物
We're talking rare flora in a secure location.
好吧 要怎么做
Okay, so, then what do we do?
首先 为说我是个乖宝宝道歉
First, apologize for calling me a goody-goody,
因为我要说的这个计划
because I'm about to lay out a plan so daring
大胆到你们俩可能都不敢进行下去
that the two of you may not have the guts to follow it.
我要带刀吗
Should I take my knife?
我车里有棒球棒
I have my baseball bat in my car.
好了 我们要偷的是辣椒
Okay, we're stealing a pepper,
不是要教训它家人
not teaching its family a lesson.
好吧
Uh, okay.
我注意到你们的一些教授
I noticed a few of your professors
坐在那种嘴巴控制的轮椅上
in those mouth-controlled wheelchairs.
我觉得他们有的只是假装看起来酷一点而已吧
I think some of them are just faking it to try and look cool.
我的个老天 机器人先生实验室
Domo Arigato, Mr. Robotics lab!
什么
What?!
对啊 来试试这里的手套 超赞
Yeah. Come check out these gloves. They're awesome.
任何动作 即便是最轻微的动作
Any movement, even the slightest motion,
这些机器手都可以照做
will be mirrored by the robotic hands.
可能应用于拆弹
Possible applications are bomb defusement,
核反应堆修复和远程神经手术
nuclear reactor repair, and remote neurosurgery.
谁只用双指就能征服每一个女机器人呢
What has two thumbs and any lady robot he wants?
这家伙
This guy.
老爸 这不是玩具
Dad, this isn't a toy.
你们好 我忠实的机器仆臣
Hello, my loyal robot subjects.
老爸
Dad?
爵士手
Jazz hands!
其他机器人在看呢
The other robots are staring!
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
最近家里怎么样
So, what's going on at home?
海莉和卢克也不怎么在家
Well, Haley and Luke aren't around much.
而且鸭子超赞的 但是没人懂
Meanwhile, the ducks are awesome and nobody gets it.
说了你可能不信 但有一只鸭子会捡东西了
You wouldn't believe this, but one of them can fetch.
我当然信
Of course I believe it.
我的一位教授
One of my professors
教会一只猩猩演奏萨克斯风
taught a chimpanzee how to play the saxophone.
我们都觉得很厉害 但是它只会演奏爵士
We all think he's great, but he only plays jazz,
所以说不定也就那样了
so there's no way to tell.
跟我说说这些家伙
Tell me about these fellas.
这个是为军队设计的
Well, this one's being developed for the military.
真的吗
Really?
那这个可爱的男孩子呢 开关你好 击个掌
What about this adorable guy? Hello, switch.
不 爸爸 别按那个
Oh, no! Dad, don't press that.
他只是去散个步
Oh, he's just going for a little walk.
总开关
The master switch!
你说啥
The what?
不 不
No, no, no!
天哪
Oh, my god.
真的发生了
It's happening!
它们造反了
They're rising up!
快关掉
Turn off!
我命令你们关掉
I command you to turn off!
关不掉了
It's not working!
我站在你这边
I'm on your side!
你为什么要那么做
Why would you do that?!
我不知道自己在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking!
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
很好 现在橄榄球队队长讨厌我了
Great. Now the captain of the football team hates me.
听好 仔细按我说的做
Okay, follow my plan to the letter,
这样十分钟后辣椒就能到手了
and in 10 minutes, we'll have peppers in hand.
今天是周六
It's Saturday.
威廉会在玫瑰园工作
William will be working the Rose Garden.
幸运的是 他不会注意到的
Fortunately, he'll be distracted.
现在 他眼里只有瓢虫
Right now, the aphids have the upper hand.
小卡 到了溪边之后
Cam, when you reach the stream,
沿着溪边朝东南方向到达蜂鸟展示园
follow it south southeast to the Hummingbird Exhibit.
不要跟任何人交流
Interact with no one.
不好意思 能给我们照张相吗
Excuse me. Could you take this for us?
这个时间我还是有的
Oh, guess I have a second.
我自拍了一张
Took a picture of myself.
现在成你的墙纸了
Oh, and now it's your wallpaper.
老妈 以免被人怀疑 多绕点路
Mom, to avoid detection, take a circuitous route
去艾德蒙及米里亚姆拉比诺维茨辣椒园
to the Edmund and Miriam Rabinowitz Pepper Patch.
带我去大红椒那边
Take me to the blood peppers.
我去引开老年参观团
I'll re-route the senior citizens' tour...
你们已经参观过这边了 而且很满意
You've already been this way. You loved it.
这样你们到辣椒那边时他们不会出现
so they're not around when you arrive at the peppers.
退下 少年
Go away, boy.
小心 可能会有额外警备
Be on alert. There may be added security.
真刺激
How exhilarating.
我都不知道我们的酱里还放了酸豆
I didn't know there was a caper in our sauce.
你怎么可能知道
How could you?
配方又不是你的
It's not your recipe.
女孩们 要不要吃点零食
Hey, girls. How about a snack?
莉莉的越南舞蹈队要来我们家过夜
I'm hosting a sleepover for Lily's Vietnamese dance troupe.
我们希望她能更亲近自己的传统
We want her to be more in touch with her heritage,
可是跟其他父母打交道
but breaking the ice with the other parents
稍微有点困难
has been a little tough.
小卡和我是父母中唯一一对白人
Cam and I are the only white parents,
唯一一对同性爱人
the only gay parents,
也是唯一觉得我们有意思的
the only parents that find us funny.
快请进 帕特里夏 陈女士
Come on in, Patricia, Ms. Tran.
女孩们都在莉莉的房间
The girls are in Lily's room.
真是有趣的巧合
Oh, this is a fun coincidence.
我们昨晚刚跟另外一对陈夫妇一起吃过晚饭
We actually had a couple Trans over for dinner last ni--
最难打交道的当属
The hardest nut to crack
小帕特里夏·陈的妈妈
has been little Patricia Tran's mother.
有次家庭聚餐我没有吃她亲手做的越南粉
I didn't try her homemade pho at a potluck once,
所以她现在讨厌我了
and now she doesn't like me.
简直可以说是"掉粉"
You could say it was a little bit of a pho pa.
你好
Hello.
-你老公吗 -我爸
- Your husband? - My dad.
我更喜欢深色头发没有小胡子的
And I prefer brunettes, without beards.
我喜欢女人
I like women.
我晚点会把帕特里夏的药拿来
I'll bring Patricia's medicine over later.
我的手袋
My purse.
她人看着挺好的
She seems nice.
外公
Hey, Grandpa!
亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart!
小贴士 你可以让这些女孩们
Little tip -- you might want the girls
把充气床吹起来
to blow up these air mattresses,
先消耗一点她们的精力
tire them out a little bit.
我没想过消耗她们的精力
Oh, I'm not trying to tire them out.
不 我是个有趣的老爸
No. I'm the fun dad, okay?
我希望她们玩得开心
I want them to have a good time.
典型新手错误
That's a rookie mistake.
你和克莱尔还小的时候
When you and Claire were kids,
我是过夜派对之王 未尝败绩
I was the sleepover champ, undefeated.
所有孩子都会在7点半之前睡着
There was never a kid that was awake later than 7:30.
不 我记得我十岁生日那天
Oh, no. I remember my 10th birthday.
你让我们给你洗车
You let us wash your car,
然后还把落地钟抬去丢掉了
and then we carried the grandfather clock to the dump.
晒太阳很重要
Yeah, sun exposure plays a big part.
这些是什么
What's this stuff?
老妈给我寄了不少她车库里的东西
Uh, Mom, uh, mailed me a bunch of stuff from her garage.
她觉得我可能喜欢旧录像带
She thought I might like a VCR and a bunch of old tapes.
迪迪给你寄垃圾真让人感动
Sweet of Dede to mail you her garbage.
《简·方达健身全集》《不是你 是他》
"Jane Fonda Complete Workouts," "It's Not You, It's Him",
《巧克力烹饪大全》
"Cooking with Chocolate."
基本上就是我们整个婚姻的艾前综合征
Pretty much the ARC of our whole marriage.
听着 如果你够聪明
Listen, if you're smart,
你会让女孩们把这些搬去捐掉
you'll let the girls walk this stuff down to Goodwill.
或者我可以为我女儿的童年
Or I could provide a fun, entertaining evening
创造一个有趣的夜晚
that will only enrich my daughter's childhood.
二爸 你能做我们尖叫比赛的评委吗
Daddy, will you judge our screaming contest?
当然了 加油哦 女孩们
Of course he will! Hit it, girls!
好吧 你们赢了 你们都赢了 平手
Okay! You won. You all won. It's a tie.
亲爱的 刚刚的事我真的很抱歉
Oh, honey, I am so sorry about what happened in there.
不用担心我 不过
Don't worry about me, but, you know,
那些机器人的程序会让它们记仇
those robots are programmed to hold a grudge.
不过跟我计划的不同
Not how I wanted this to go.
大概要过很久
Probably gonna be a while
我才会再被邀请来这了吧
before I get invited back here, huh?
老爸 没关系
Dad, it's okay.
反正你也会更常见到我
You're probably going to be seeing me a lot more,
因为我打算搬回家
considering I want to move back home
下学期走读
and commute to school next semester.
真的吗
Really?
是啊 反正开车只要半小时
Yeah. It's only a half-hour drive.
你生气了吗
Are you mad?
生气 怎么可能 我好兴奋
Mad? Are you kidding me? I'm thrilled.
我超级想你的
You know how much I miss you.
我们可以在车库里建自己的机器人实验室
We could have our own robot lab in the garage.
那得花多少钱啊
How much could that possibly cost?
可是 为什么呢 发生什么事了
But, uh -- but why? Did something happen?
没有 只是...
No, it's just --
这里的人太幼稚了
Ugh, the people here are all so immature.
他们老是用啤酒杯装着玛格丽特
They are always banging on your door
来敲你的门 而且...
with a beaker full of margaritas, and...
那群书呆子烦得要命
The nerd noise is deafening.
你把我让老妈准备的降噪耳罩带来了吗
Did you bring those noise-canceling headphones I asked mom for?
抱歉 我忘了
Oh, I am so sorry. I forgot.
有时候我大脑会自动过滤你妈说的话
Sometimes my brain cancels out your mom's noise.
你上课的时候我去买一个
I'll, uh -- I'll pick some up
然后给你放到寝室来
while you're in class and then drop them by the dorm.
谢谢
Thanks.
抱歉
Excuse me.
今晚是加农炮之夜 别错过哦
Cannon Ball tonight. Don't miss it.
不用了 谢谢
Oh, no, no. Thanks.
那是什么
What's that about?
这里的一个愚蠢的传统
Oh, it's just some stupid tradition where,
每学期结束的时候
at the end of the semester,
所有大一生都要穿着晚礼服裙
all the freshmen jump off a high dive
高台跳水
in cheesy prom dresses.
应该很有趣
Oh, that could be fun.
肯定不会
It definitely won't be.
不如你去试试看...
Well, maybe if you give it a chance...
不 老爸 我告诉你
No. You know what, Dad?
我去过了
I-I-I did.
我已经去过大概十个派对
I've -- I've already been to like 10 parties,
都很无聊
and they're all lame.
每个人都只跟自己室友聊天
Everyone just talks to their own dorm mate.
亲爱的 有时候融入人群中是需要时间的
Sweetie, sometimes it takes a while to warm up to people.
讲这些干嘛 你不想让我回家吗
What is this about? Do you not want me to come home?
是因为这样吗
Is that what this is?
我自己在校园外租个公寓好了
Because, fine, I'll just go get an apartment off campus.
艾丽克斯 别生气
Alex, don't get mad.
我气坏了
Well, I am mad.
因为我真的有自知之明
Because I'm actually smart enough
我能看出什么适合我什么不适合
to know what's working for me and what isn't,
而这个就不适合
And this isn't.
我要去上课了
I have to go to class.
小心 当心
Heads up! Watch out!
这也太神了吧
How'd he do that?
米奇尔
Mitchell?
在厨房 外公
In the kitchen, grandpa!
越南女孩和一个浓妆男人
Vietnamese girls and a man in makeup.
鲍勃·霍普什么时候出来表演
When does Bob Hope take the stage?
真会说笑
Delightful.
充气床垫弄好了
You're good to go on the air mattresses.
祝你今晚好运
Good luck with the sleepover.
怎么了 女士
Yes, Ma'am?
我不想再当有趣老爸了
I don't want to be the fun dad anymore.
我想让这些女孩快点累趴下
I need to knock these girls out quick.
快教我
Teach me.
开始吧 女士们 伸高点
Let's go, ladies! Reach to the sky!
为什么你比简·方达还擅长这个
How are you better at this than Jane Fonda?
米奇尔 你要是讲话
Mitchell, you can't talk
就感受不到脂肪燃烧了
and feel the burn at the same time.
使劲向外踢 珍妮弗
Donkey-kick like you mean it, Jennifer.
我很好奇 这带子应该在前往慈善机构的路上
I'm just curious, because this tape was on its way to Goodwill,
可突然间 你却从后口袋把它掏出来了
and all of a sudden, you pulled it out of your back pocket.
我胖了几斤
I put on a couple of extra pounds,
简曾在八十年代帮我解决了这个问题
and Jane got me out of a similar situation in the ’80s.
你当时不会穿了暖腿套[女性瘦身操道具]吧
Please tell me you were wearing leg warmers.
别烦我
Leave me alone.
我们行的 孩子们 踏起步来
We got this, girls. March it out.
且不论值不值 老爸 我是没看出来你胖了
Well, for whatever it's worth, Dad, I didn't notice.
歌洛莉亚看出来了
Gloria did.
她用手戳了我肚子上的嘟嘟肉
She did that little poke thing to my spare tire.
莉莉 保持节奏
Lily, keep the beat.
我很不想承认 但这真的烦死我了
I hate to admit it, but it bugged the hell out of me.
金丽 这才是出拳和迈步的节奏
Kim-ly, we're punching and we're stepping.
能不能跟上
Care to join us?
我觉得我要每天都做这个锻炼
So, I figured I'd do this workout every damn day of the week
直到我的肚臀腿遍布筋肉
until I was nothing but abs, buns, and thighs.
屁股动起来 蒂芙尼
Work your glutes, Tiffany!
这正是你要减的部位
This is your problem area.
好吧 老爸 无意冒犯
Okay, Dad, no offense, but I've been listening
但是自从你60岁时
to you whine about gaining and losing the same 10 pounds
娶了世界上最漂亮的女人后
since, at age 60,
我就一直在听你讲这得而复失的几斤体重
you married the most beautiful woman in the world.
尽管我能理解这是有钱白人烦恼中
And while I appreciate what might be the rich-white-mannest
最有"有钱白人"特点的问题
of rich-white-man problems,
但这带子硬是把这些小女孩弄兴奋了
this tape is only energizing these little girls.
这好无聊
This is boring.
我们去我房间搭堡垒吧
Let's go and build a fort in my room.
所以怎样 你就这样放弃了
So, what? You're just gonna give up?
人得知道什么时候投降
You got to know when to surrender.
不 长官
No, sir.
我可不想一生两次输给越南人
I'm not losing to the Vietnamese twice in a lifetime.
快起来
Get up.
谁都不能被落下[美军格言]
No man left behind.
看这高尔夫球场 这会是鸭子们的美丽家园
Look at this golf course. It's a beautiful home for ducks.
来 谁要帮我
Okay, now, who's gonna help me
把这些小混蛋放生了
set these little suckers free, huh?
-你放吧 -我不要
- You do it. - I'm good.
给点力啊
Oh, come on.
我们都讨厌这些鸭子 想让他们消失啊
We all hate the ducks. We all want them gone.
为什么我就得当那坏人呢
Why do I have to be the bad guy?
我不知道 为什么我就负责貌美如花呢
I don't know. Why am I the pretty one?
我们都各有所长
We all have our thing.
好吧 好吧 我来吧
Fine. Fine. I'll do it.
快出来 这就好了 你们自由了
Get on out there. There you go. You're free. Okay.
他们怎么哪儿都不去呢
Why aren't they going anywhere?
自恋小姐还在那儿做准备呢
Well, Miss Thing over there is still getting herself ready.
我发誓她一早上
I swear she spent all morning
都在欣赏自己在碗里的倒影呢
looking at her reflection in the water bowl.
那只怪胎呢
How about that weirdo?
你们昨天有看到他嘴巴卡在笼子上了吗
Did you see when he got his bill stuck in his cage yesterday?
多可爱的小笨蛋啊
What a sweet little dope.
我知道 还好他有个聪明的姐姐
I know. He's lucky his sister is so smart.
她弄清了怎么打开笼子
You know, she figured out how to unlatch the cage
放他自由
and set him free.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
你们明白这是什么情况了吗
Do you guys see what's happening?
-没 -你们当然没看出来
- No. - Of course you don't.
你爸之所以这么痴迷于这些鸭子
The reason why your dad is so attached to these ducks
是因为鸭子让他想起了你们
is they remind him of you guys.
我们得把他们带回家
We got to get them home.
他们不见了
They're gone.
天啊
Oh, my god.
他们去哪儿了
Where are they?
天哪
Oh, God.
搞什么
What the hell?
难道大家都把鸭子扔到这里吗
Does everyone get rid of their ducks here?
我们能随便抓三只吗
Can't we just pick any three?
你爸一眼就会看出来的
Your father will know immediately.
看 我觉得那只是卢克小笨鸭
Look. I think that might be the dumb Luke duck.
在逗其他鸭子乐的那只吗
The one entertaining the others?
它的头被零食袋套住了
His head is caught in the Fritos bag.
-那不是你的鸭吗 -哪里
- Isn't that your duck? - Where?
那只用鸭嘴来回捣鼓麦子 想吃又不敢吃
The one pushing oats around with its beak, pretending to eat.
那就是了 去把鸭子抓回来 快去
All right. That's it. Go get your ducks. Go.
什么 不 水里又脏又浑的
What? No. It is filthy and filmy.
而且卢克都还没下去呢
And that's before Luke even gets in it.
要是抓不到第三只鸭子
What's the point in getting two ducks
抓来两只又有什么用呢
if we don't have the third one?
我们要怎么找到艾丽克斯那只鸭呢
And how are we supposed to find the Alex duck?
等到新年前夕 看看哪只待在家
Wait until New Year's Eve and see which one stays home?
不 不 你说对了
No. No. You're right.
我们要集齐三只鸭子才能回家
We are not going home without all three ducks.
等等 看看你爸说的是不是真的
Hang on. Let's see if your dad was right.
小羽
Feather.
小羽 快去捡
Feather. Fetch.
怎么可能
No way.
不要干站着 快去抓你们的鸭子
Don't just stand there. Get your ducks.
我刚花了一周的薪水买的这双鞋
I just spent a week's salary on these shoes.
我才不 瞧那双棕色的大眼睛
I'm not -- oh, look at those big brown eyes.
占了她半张脸呢
They take up half her face!
我来了 小公主
I'm coming, princess!
借过
Pardon me.
抱歉 玩得开心
Sorry. Have fun.
用铀做的最危险的饼是什么
What's the most dangerous type of uranium cake?
黄饼[哈啰]
Yellow!
你怎么啦
What's going on?
我捡到了个吸入器 你知道是谁的吗
I found this inhaler. Do you know whose it is?
这儿只有六个人不用这个的
There's only six people here who don't use those.
他们毕业的时候会一起抛到空中
They throw them in the air at graduation.
好吧
All right.
你把降噪耳罩带来了吗
Hey, did you bring those headphones?
有 在这儿
Yeah. Right here.
谢啦
Thanks.
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
刚才的事很抱歉
I'm sorry about earlier.
回到大学校园可能让我想起了过去
I think maybe being on a college campus took me back,
使我的新生焦虑感重现了
and some of my own first-year insecurities bubbled up.
我谁都不认识 而且无论我多努力
I didn't know anybody, and no matter how hard I tried,
我却始终是个局外人
I was always on the outside.
然后突然有一天 不知为何 我融入进去了
And then suddenly, one day, something clicked and I was in.
我是说 这很难说的
I mean, you never know.
就算对你是这种情况
I mean, just because that happened to you,
-并不意味着 -不 不 不 不
- Doesn't mean that's -- - No, no, no, no, no.
我想说的就是这个
That's -- that's my point.
你和我不一样
My story isn't your story.
虽然这地方令人生畏
As intimidating as this place may be,
但我从未见过你轻易向困难低过头
I've never seen you walk away from a challenge.
如果你说已经尽力了
If you tell me you've given it your best shot,
那我相信你
then I know you have.
别生我的气好吗
So don't be mad at me, okay?
我没生气
I'm not mad.
那就好 宝贝
All right, kiddo.
你妈妈和我下周会过来帮你收拾行李
Your mom and I will be back next week to pack you up.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
-再见 -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
好了 老爷爷礼品篮的卡车还有84分钟就到
Okay. Granddaddy's truck's gonna be here in 84 minutes.
所以继续拧紧瓶盖 搅拌 切菜
So, we're tightening, we're stirring, we're chopping.
快装瓶[克制]吧
Bottle it up!
我不行 太紧张了
I can't. I'm just too excited.
你说得是把酱装瓶 明白了
you mean the sauce in the -- got it. Yes.
小卡
Cam...
-这是什么 -老天
- What is this? - Oh, my gosh.
这本不该让你看见的
You weren't supposed to see these yet.
可这上面根本就没有我
But I am not even on it.
不 有你的 有你 你看
No, you are. Yes, you are. See?
营养成分表这里有你的剪影
You're the silhouette right here by the nutritional facts.
这样 人们会关注你的身段
That way, people are looking at you
就不会关注那些超剂量的钠了
and not the toxic amount of sodium.
我这还有别的样本
I have others, too.
有一张是我们其中一个人坐着辣椒火箭
You know, I have one of us on a pepper rocket
冲向《酱料城》节目
on our way to Flavor City.
你在我前面 那张很可爱的
You're in front of me, and it's cute.
我觉得咱俩的合作没戏
You know what? I don't think this partnership is working.
你说什么呢
What are you saying?
我说什么
What am I saying?
这是我家传的酱料
This is family's sauce,
而你已经试图更改配方
and you have already tried to change the recipe.
你连问都没问我就接了那么大个订单
You took a huge order without even asking me.
现在又来这一套
And now this?
如果要上《酱料城》 也是我自己上
If I am going to Flavor City, I am going by myself.
你要跟我散伙[分手]吗
You're breaking up with me?
当我刚开始跟小卡约会时
When I first started dating Cam,
他的前男友就提醒过我
his ex-boyfriend gave me a heads up.
他说 小卡是个很好的人
He said, "Cam's a great guy,
我希望你永远别跟他分手
but I hope you never have to break up with him."
我问他 为什么 他会生气
And I said, "Why? Does he get angry,
哭泣 嫉妒 沮丧吗
weepy, jealous, despondent?"
他说 是的
He said, "Yes."
你要跟我散伙吗
You're breaking up with me?
这个合伙的主意是我想出来的
This business was my idea.
是我带你去农贸市场的
I got you into the farmers' market.
是我让你的酱料被老爷爷品牌选中
I got you into those baskets.
我发现你时 你不过就是个家庭主妇
You were nothing but a housewife when I found you.
我没别的意思 我一直很欣赏你的
I didn't mean that. I've always admired you.
做家庭主妇是这世界上最难的工作
Being a housewife is the hardest job on the planet.
从来都没有休息的时间
You're never not at work.
只是 我们怎么会走到这一步的
It's just -- how did we get to this place?
除非...
Unless...
你有别的合伙人了 是不是
There's someone else, isn't there?
我怎么会这么傻呢
Oh, how could I be so blind?
让我猜猜 那人经验更丰富吧
Let me guess -- somebody with more experience?
是个哥伦比亚人吧
Somebody Colombian?
你也轻松不了的
Well, you're no picnic, either.
到底是谁
So, who is it?
说话啊
Say something!
我见过我妈跟许多男人分手
I've seen my mom break up with a lot of guys.
她总是有魔力让他们把责任都包揽在自己身上
She has this weird power to get them to do all the work.
前一分钟 他们还很生气
One minute, they're a mess.
而后一分钟 他们就开始感谢她
The next, they're thanking her
说跟她在一起的时光是人生中最美好的
for the best year of their lives.
上一个分手的家伙还帮我们把行李搬到了杰家
The last guy helped us move into Jay's house.
你早就知道
You knew.
你早知道我需要激励才能创造出属于自己的酱料
You knew I needed the motivation to create my own sauce.
你一直都知道的
You knew all along.
不客气的 小卡 别担心
You're welcome, Cam. And don't worry.
我知道总有一天 你自创的酱料
I know that one day, you're gonna have your sauce
会被老爷爷礼品篮选中的
in Granddaddy's Basket.
这景倒是稀奇
Well, that paints a picture.
你看 这里有很多东西都可以把孩子们累倒
Now, see, there's lots of stuff here to tire the kids out.
可以搬砖 可以用铁铲挖土
Look -- bricks for carrying, shovels for digging.
铁铲 我们什么时候有铁铲了
Shovels. When did we get shovels?
好了 不管你们在做什么
Okay, well, whatever you're doing,
能不能麻烦你们换个地方
can you do it someplace else?
我在帮歌洛莉亚的酱料装瓶
I'm helping Gloria bottle her sauce,
我们就要来不及了
and we're running out of time.
小卡 我觉得已经来不及了
Ay, Cam. I think it's too late.
剩下的时间不够了
I don't think we have enough time to finish.
或许可以
You might.
陈女士 这是帕特里夏的药吗
Oh, Ms. Tran. Is that Patricia's medicine?
加快速度 姑娘们
Pick up the pace, ladies!
快点 我们只剩下20分钟了
Come on! We've only got 20 minutes!
相信我 其实比看起来稍微好那么一点
Trust me. This is slightly better than it looks.
我的手指头疼
My fingers hurt.
宝贝 我不是说了流水线上不能说话吗
Hey, honey, what did I say about talking on the line?
好吧 我们把这些鸭子尽快
Okay. Let's just get these ducks back into the garage
放回车库 别出声
as fast as we can, and please be quiet.
-别让你父亲听见 -你们好啊
- I don't want your father to hear us. - Hello.
我提前回家了 看到你们六个
I got home early and noticed the six of you
不在家[鸭子出门]
had...ducked out.
我们知道你有多爱这些鸭子
Well, we know how much you love the ducks,
而且我们也想跟他们一起玩
and -- and we wanted to play with them, too.
-而我们... -而什么 克莱尔
- And we -- - And what, Claire?
最疯狂的事发生了是吗
The craziest thing happened?
你来了个急转弯 笼子门开了
You turned a hard corner, the cage banged open,
有一只鸭子碰到了天窗按钮
one of them hit the sunroof button,
他们就都飞出去了 只剩下一个空...
and out they flew, leaving us with nothing but an empty --
我打扰你们了 请继续
I interrupted you. Go on.
虽然我们有时候不太喜欢这些鸭子 菲尔
We have not always loved the ducks, Phil,
但我们开始理解你了
but I think we're starting to get it.
是啊 我们想让他们留下
Yeah. We want them to stay.
我们知道你为何爱他们了
We know why you love them.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
我一直都知道 这些小捣蛋们
I always knew it was only a matter of time
迟早会摇摇晃晃地走到你们的心里去
before these little scamps waddled into your hearts
就像他们走进我的心一样
just like they did mine.
现在来吧 帮我把他们从窗户扔出去
Now, come on. Help me throw them out the window.
老爸 你在干什么
Dad, what are you doing?
是时候该让他们离开了
It is time for them to go.
可是 亲爱的 你确定他们会飞了吗
But, honey, are you sure they can even fly?
据网上资料所述 一个月前他们就该会飞了
According to the internet, they were ready a month ago.
早餐时 你还给他们揉肩膀呢
At breakfast, you were giving them shoulder rubs.
出什么事了
What happened?
今天我意识到 可能是我拖他们后腿了
I realized today that I may have been holding them back
因为他们是我的快乐
because that was fun for me.
但到了最后
But in the end,
还是得放手让他们自由飞翔 不是吗
you got to let them spread their wings, right?
-加油 姑娘 -加油 艾丽克斯
- Whoo! Let's go! Girl! - All right, Alex!
好了 各位 我们开始吧
All right, guys. Let's do this.
一 二...
One, two...
要回来看我们哦
Come visit us!
别走错路哦
Make good choices!
从某种意义上说 是你们捡回了我
In many ways, you fetched me!
被你发现了
You caught me.
我知道他们不会回来了
I know they're not coming back.
有时候会的
Sometimes they do.
喂
Hello?
艾丽克斯
Hey, Alex.
怎么样 宝贝
What's going on, sweetheart?
是吗
Yeah?
当下面的弹簧铰链也固定好
"Once the lower spring hinge is secured,
就可以把衣橱门装上了
you can then attach the closet door."
她们都睡了 米奇
They're all sleeping, Mitch.
还不错
Not bad.
用时45分 还有进步的空间
45. Room for improvement.
看来本王依旧立于不败之地
Well, it looks like I'm still undefeated.